- Every time I recommend exercises like fan pull-aparts or face pulls, the hypertrophy
bros and the evidence-based lifters all come after me.
They'll say things like, "There's not enough mechanical tension," or "They have poor loadability."
No shit, Sherlock.
Not every exercise in your program has to be everything.
Now should you be programming highly loadable exercises you can progress over time?
Absolutely.
Rows, squats, presses should be the foundation of most programs.
But exercises are like players on a football team.
They all have separate roles.
For example, Tom Brady is the greatest quarterback of all time, but a team with 22 Tom Brady's
would go 0-17 because he'd make a really shitty offensive tackle or linebacker.
Again, every player has a role, and so does every exercise.
Band pull-aparts and face pulls aren't going to build a Mr. Olympia level back on their
own.
They're role players.
They could prime muscles, add volume without adding excess fatigue, help keep your shoulders
healthy, and simply complement your heavier work.
In my opinion, the best programs don't consist of 10 optimal exercises.
They combine different exercises that do different jobs and make the entire program better.
And speaking of programs, the new programs section of my website is officially live.
If you want to check out 8 of my most popular training programs, comment "programs" and
I'll send you the link.
Every time I recommend you check out 8 of my most popular training programs, comment